## SAIKIRAN GOUD, BURRA

Kansas, USA ♦ H: 8324682441 ♦ saikiran.af72@gmail.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Highly skilled software development professional bringing more than 6 years in software design, development, and integration in agile. Advanced knowledge of building webservices, microservices and streaming services using Java, Kotlin, Spring boot, Apache Spark, Kafka, AWS, CI/CD pipelines, Linux, and GIT.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Executive Master's in Business Administration**: Information Technology June 2023

Ottawa University - Overland Park, Kansas

Master of Science: Computer Science, GPA: 3.5/4.0 May 2018

University of Houston - Houston, Texas

Bachelor of Engineering: Information Technology, GPA: 3.7/4.0 May 2014

Osmania University - Hyderabad, India

#### EXPERIENCE

### Senior Software Engineer – Securonix Inc – Dallas, USA

July 2021 to Present

Securonix is a cyber security company providing security analytics and management platform as a service using big data analytics.

- Designed and developed a high-performance migration system using Spark and Kafka to migrate 90 million records in the Solr database reducing downtime of the application from 10 hrs. to 4 hrs.
- Took ownership of Risk score analysis streaming job and worked towards improving application code quality independently.
- Participated in design discussions with System architects and QA to develop a low-latency streaming application and developed to handle 10,000 requests per 5 seconds.
- Responsible for deploying applications in AWS EC2 and on-premises client environments, monitoring dashboards by rotational support in the team.
- Implemented POC to migrate from Java to Kotlin as part of continuous improvement and learning.

### **Software Engineer – Oracle Cerner** – Kansas City, USA

July 2018 to July 2021

Oracle Cerner is a Health Software company providing wide range of products including Electronic Health Records, Revenue Cycle, and Patient Portals.

- Designed and improved the performance of SMART Health IT application rendering within Cerner's Revenue Cycle application by 40% and fixed significant security flaws.
- Troubleshoot production issues in the client environment and provided high-quality code quick fixes.
- Mentored junior team members, providing educational expertise on technical concepts, and assisted in system design of project tasks.
- As part of migrating existing application, I am working on AWS services cloud formation, IAM, SNS, SQS, and S3 buckets.
- Took the initiative to use React-on-Rails in the desktop application by launching a system browser which increased team efficiency by 50% by using React as a UI framework.
- Responsible for creating microservices in Koltin to handle OAuth authentication as well as launch UI using spring boot.

# Software Engineering Intern - NetIQ, Micro Focus — Houston, USA

May 2017 to August 2017

NetIQ provides identity and access management, security, and data center management.

- Migrate Postgresql SQL scripts to Oracle queries to run efficiently and improve query performance.
- Involved in creating Business Intelligence tools to streamline the database report development process and add functionality, using a custom JavaScript tool that accepted JSON and outputs XML report display.

### Project Engineer - Wipro Technologies Ltd - Hyderabad, India

**August 2014 to July 2016** 

Wipro Limited is an Indian multinational corporation that provides information technology, consulting, and business process services.

- Performed full life cycle development of complex commercial enterprise applications leveraging objectoriented Java and J2EE technologies, SQL and agile.
- Extended our platform functionality to support web-related functions in RCP Application.
- Led a team of 15 in developing and securing Web Application, SOAP and RESTful Web services Development, SOA, EDI, System Analysis, Technical Design, A2A, and B2B Development, Implementation, Performance Tuning, and Testing.
- Managed to learn Python scripting to develop SFTP operations by understanding legacy bash scripts.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages	Java, C++, Python, Kotlin, Ruby
J2EE Frameworks	Java 8 streams, Functional Interfaces, Spring,
	Spring REST, Microservices, Spring Boot, Hibernate
	ORM, JSP, Servlets.
Big Data Technologies	Apache Spark, Apache Flink, Hbase, HDFS,
	MapReduce, Kafka, Solr, Redis, and Elastic Search.
Cloud Technologies	AWS S3, SNS, SQS, IAM, EC2, Lambda
Operations Technologies	Jenkins, Bamboo, GitHub CI/CD, Docker, Grafana,
	Kubernetes, Spinnaker, Data Dog, New Relic
Web Services	SOAP, REST
Operating Systems	Windows, Unix, MacOS
Databases	Oracle, PostgreSQL
Version Control Tools	SVN, Git
SDLC	Agile, Waterfall
Testing Tools	Junit, Mockito, Power Mock, and Spring Test
Development Tools	Postman, VisualVM, IntelliJ, Sublime Text, Eclipse,
	Visual Studio Code
Build Tools	Ant, Maven, and Gradle